VANDANA KARAN

<u>Vandana.karan.101@gmail.com</u> | New York, New York | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vandana-karan/

SUMMARY

UX Researcher with 3 years of experience in technology research & development, seeking a mixed-methods or qualitative UX Research role. I have led multiple efforts across the design thinking process, including generative research and ideation for new products. Prior to transitioning into UX Research, I worked as a software engineer and data scientist, where I learned to design optimized solutions, perform data analysis, and make empirical decisions. Looking to leverage my analytical skills in a UX Research role.

SKILLS

UX Methods: Interviews, Surveys, Persona Development, Usability Testing, UX Benchmarking, Data Analysis **Languages:** python, R, SQL

CERTIFICATIONS

UX Certificate (Specialty in UX Research), Nielsen-Norman Group

Completion: Apr 2022

Relevant Courses: User Interviews, Usability Testing, Measuring UX and ROI, Statistics for UX

SELECTED PROJECTS

Clearviction Apr 2022 - Present

- Compiled data received from SME interviews, ethnographic research, and surveys to assess major needs, frustrations, and behaviors for our target user persona.
- Design moderated-usability test to assist with ongoing product development.

Schwab: Virtual Reality (VR) Enhanced Data Visualization Exploration

May 2021 - Nov 2021

- Led exploration to determine whether virtual reality could assist individuals with data analysis.
- Produced generative research on assessing the potential use and value of VR-based data visualizations.
- Interviewed 5 potential users to identify problems that can be addressed with Virtual Reality.
- Presented top findings to stakeholders, finalizing 3 valuable applications of VR for data visualizations.

Schwab: Contactless Experiences Innovation Lab

Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

- Collaborated with product, designers, and engineers to develop contactless experiences.
- Collected and analyzed app and client data to inform persona development.
- Assisted with user interviews to understand financial service issues unique to the Covid-19 pandemic.
- Synthesized results from UX concept testing to propose 10 concepts with high value.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Research Lead Apr 2022 – Present

Clearviction - Remote I Volunteer, Part-Time

- Develop research methods and strategies for improving the Clearviction product.
- Establish plans for recruiting test participants, and delivering feedback to product and stake

R&D Engineer Mar 2019 – Present

Charles Schwab - Remote | Full-Time

- Conduct primary and secondary research on financial planning clients to identify new product opportunities.
- Implement new ideation techniques to help R&D align innovative technology with user needs.
- Pilot machine learning based automation proof-of-concepts for the firm.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science/Finance

Sep 2014 - Dec 2018

Northeastern University - Boston, MA

Awards: Ronald Takaki Award for Community Engagement